Finding aid for the Barbara Aziz broadcasts collection
Bentley Historical Library
- Radio Tahrir and related material, 1989-2014
  - March 2, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:06:09); (Aziz news report, Obeid and Griggs report on growth of Muslim activists and services, ICNA (Islamic Circle of North America) and "The Message" magazine. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Aziz report from Palestine with Ryme Katkhouda, NY community leaders Sheik Obeid and Khalid Griggs; Portland activist Aseel Dyck. Topics: Palestine, economy, US Palestinians in West Bank, Muslim Americans, ICNA Muslim network, Iraq.)
  - March 9, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:03:31); (Lazreg's book "Eloquence of Silence", Kathouda reviews children\'s magazine and speaks to its editor Tayyibah Taylor, KA Jihad reports on work with US homeless. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: author NY-Hunter College prof Marnia Lazreg, Ryme Katkhouda, Muslim editor Tayyibah Taylor, Khatib Akbar Jihad, UMMAH (Muslim org for homelessness). Topics: women, Algerian women, education, history; children\'s books, Islam, Muslim services.)
  - March 30, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:30:16); (Review of South African Muslim Conference, Al-Hibri offers overview of women in Islam today compared with early history. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Arab Voice Crescent Rising edition: Islamic scholar/ attorney Azizah Al-Hibri. Topics: South African Muslim conference women, Islam, Islamic health practices.)
  - April 6, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:06:02); (Aziz and Ibrahim discuss confrontation and dispute in Denver sports event and other anti-Muslim actions, reading of children's story. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Mahmoud Ibrahim reports on Mahmoud Abdul Raouf Denver sports figure, Sommieh Uddin, NJ Muslim teacher. Topics: US civil rights, Muslim activism, anti-Muslim actions and films, children's book.)
  - April 13, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:04:01); (Harris describes work of MPF and partnership with Fellowship of Reconciliation (FOR) in Bosnia children scholarship program in US; clip from "Sarajevo Mon Amour" and interview with director. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Rabia Harris, NY-based Muslim Peace Fellowship director and editor, Bosnia Theater group. Topics: Islam, Muslim Americans, Bosnia.)
  - June 1, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 01:06:20); (Flounders details sanctions on Iraq and limits of 986 UN resolution, Ambassador Nizar Hamdoon assesses this UN resolution, Nita Renfrew criticizes framework of resolution. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Sara Flounders of International Action Center, NY; Iraqi UN Ambassador Nizar Hamdoon, journalist Nita Renfrew. Topics: Iraq, sanctions, destruction and health.)
  - June 22, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:07:08); (Abdul Wahab reviews her work under sanctions; AlAdawiya reports on Women in Islam's work and aims. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim. Interviewees/Guests: Iraq-based artist Samira Abdul Wahab, Aisha AlAdawiya, Director of Women in Islam, Barbara Nimri Aziz reports on NJ Muslim leadership conference. Topics: Iraq, modern art, Islam, women, civil rights, activism in US politics.)
  - August 1996, (A three hour special in 2 parts with testimonials, analyses, and commentaries)
    - Part 1 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:29:32); (Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: co-host Mahmoud Ibrahim, journalist Robert Knight, veteran Carol Picou, attorney Ramsey Clark, Eric Hopkins, Sara Flounders, Nita Renfrew, Kuwaiti MP Abdallah Nibari, Phyllis Bennis. Topics: Iraq, sanctions, health, anti-war, veterans, UN policies.)
    - Part 2 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:27:42); (Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: same. Topics: Iraq, sanctions, health, anti-war, veterans, UN policies.)
  - September 14, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:13:07); (Ibrahim Gonzalez reads and produces his Sufi segment, "Reading of the Heart." Interviewees/Guests: Ibrahim Gonzalez, musician NY-based. Topics: Islam, Sufi, poetry.)
  - November 30, 1996
    - Part 1 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:26:06); (Aziz interviews Joanna Kadi, author of "Thinking Class", Minneapolis. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: author Joanna Kadi. Editor of "Food For Our Grandmothers". Topics: Arab American literature, poetry.)
    - Part 2 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:23:03); (Ibrahim speaks with Hamad re her new books, "Drops of this Story" and "Born Palestinian, Born Black." Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim. Interviewees/Guests: Suheir Hammad, poet, actor, NY-based. Topics: Arab American literature, poetry.)
  - December 7, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:50:46); (Interview with author of "Arabs and Israel for Beginners," Kathouda reviews history of Palestinian dispossession, callins. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NJ-based author Ron David, producer Ryme Kathouda. Topics: Arab American, Palestine, Israel.)
  - Maqam: From Cordoba to Baghdad series, circa 1997
    - Part 1 of 5, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:26:52); (Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Simon Shaheen, NY-based composer, musician. Topics: Middle East, music.)
    - Part 2 of 5, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:40); (Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Simon Shaheen, NY-based composer, musician. Topics: Middle East, music.)
    - Part 3 of 5, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:27:16); (Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Simon Shaheen, NY-based composer, musician. Topics: Middle East, music.)
    - Part 4 of 5, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:25:39); (Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Simon Shaheen, NY-based composer, musician. Topics: Middle East, music.)
    - Part 5 of 5, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:30:43); (Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Simon Shaheen, NY-based composer, musician. Topics: Middle East, music.)
  - January 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:01); (Samara criticizes "Hebron Deal" of 1997 and how it fits into wider policy for West Bank, continued Jewish settlements. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Adel Samara, Ramallah based economist and writer, interviewed in West Bank. Topics: Palestine, economy, Palestinian Authority, corruption, Oslo Peace Accord, The Hebron Deal, Israeli policy.)
  - January 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:56); (Ramadan Program, Bouziane reviews Rai music and reviews characteristics and leading musicians of this tradition. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim. Interviewees/Guests: intern Ryme Katkhouda, Rai music and film critic Anissa Bouziane. Topics: Algeria, North African Rai music.)
  - January 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:40); (Cleary from a commercial recording; Gonzalez's production "Readings from the Heart". Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim. Interviewees/Guests: Tomas Cleary, religious history scholar; Ibrahim Gonzalez musician. Topics: Islam, religion.)
  - January 11, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:48); (Ibish reviews Israeli-Syrian talks, music virtuoso Simon Shaheen parts Part 4 and 5 (of 5 Part series) of "From Cordoba to Baghdad" interviewed by Barbara Nimri Aziz. Hosts/Producer: Jad Abumrad. Interviewees/Guests: Political observer Hussein Ibish, music educator and virtuoso Simon Shaheen. Topics: Syria, Israel, Arab music history and theory.)
  - January 18, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:06:58); (Gonzalez' poetic music production for Ramadan, Thomas Cleary speaks about religion, politics and slavery, Salloum describes special Arab vegetarian dishes. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim. Interviewees/Guests: intern Ryme Katkhouda, Sufi musician Ibrahim Gonzalez, CA-based Prof Tom Cleary, author Habeeb Salloum. Topics: Ramadan, Muslim Americans, slavery, Islam, food and culture.)
  - February 22, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:03:30); (Hussein comments on Syrian political strategies in the region, Abu Sabe describes growth of NJ Muslims and relations with state; Iraq doctors interviewed in Kerbala describes 6 years of sanctions on health care. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: political observer Hussein Ibish, NJ community leader Abu Saba, Kerbala Iraqi doctors. Topics: Syria, Iraq, NJ Muslims- Arab Americans.)
  - March 1, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:36); (Dr. Nafii reviews health conditions in Iraq (interviewed in Kerbala), listener calls; report on US anti-Muslim biases, pt1 with Taliban member Abdul Hakim Mujahid visiting US. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Taliban Abdul Hakim Mujahid, Iraq medical Dr. Karim Nafii, intern Ryme Katkhouda. Topics: Iraq, sanctions, medical, civil rights, media biases, Afghanistan.)
  - circa March 1, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:43:38); (During rule of Taliban, this representative explains what he is doing in the US in regards to development of his country and end of warlords. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Abdul Hakim Mujahid, Taliban representative in NY. Topics: Afghanistan, leadership and policies.)
  - March 8, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:04:35); (Celebrating women's history, recording of Palestinian woman folk singer (in Arabic); Bouziane reviews film on famed Egyptian vocalist Um Khultum, Egyptian feminist Doria Shafiq, author professor Cynthia Nelson speaks about feminist Doria Safiq inter Suzy Kane; Kathouda interview Salima Ghazale, Algerian editor and journalist. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Anissa Bouziane. Interviewees/Guests: Palestinian singer Um Talal, film critic Anissa Bouziane, intern Ryme Katkhouda, Algerian editor Salima Ghazale, Suzy Kane and Prof Cynthia Nelson. Topics: Arab women, Middle East.)
  - March 15, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:41); (Ibish comments on continued Israeli settlement and UN vote, poems, Abu Sabe updates on Muslim rights and involvement in NJ state, Sadoon talks with Aziz re Iraqi sanctions and corruption of latest UN resolution on oil sales. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: political observer Hussein Ibish, poets Suheir Hammad and H. Hawat, NJ-political observer Murad Abu Sabe, Iraqi economist Nasra Sadoon, intern Ryme Katkhouda. Topics: Palestine, Israeli occupation settlement policy, UN vote, poetry, NJ community actions; Iraq sanctions and UN resolution on oil sales.)
  - April 5, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:01:18); (Ibish's third overview of Saudi Arabian civil and economic policies, Bouziane reviews 4 films by Arab directors showing in NY festival, and criticism of Nike shoe image of Allah. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Amherst-based political commentator Hussein Ibish, film critic Anissa Bouziane, CAIR Media director Ibrahim Hooper. Topics: Saudi Arabia, civil rights, US policy, Arab film review, anti-Islam bias.)
  - April 12, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:11); (Sherif reviews Muslims in local politics, Gonzalez reports history and work of Latino organization Alianza Islamica, legal reports on defense of political US-Palestinian prisoner Abu Marzouk, Ibish comments on decline of Oslo Accords, clip of interview with Taliban leader. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NJ-community representative Carl Sherif, commentator Hussein Ibish, Taliban Rep, Latino-Muslim Ibrahim Gonzalez. Topics: NJ-NY area elections and candidates, Muslim Eid Al-Adha, Latino Muslims.)
  - April 19, 1997
    - Part 1 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:24:09); (Ibish comments on Israeli policy construction of new settlements and weak role of Palestinian Authority. Hosts/Producer: Mamoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Hussein Ibish political commentator. Topics: Israeli settlements and occupation of Palestine, US policy.)
    - Part 2 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:38:15); (Bouziane reviews Rai music, Sommieh Uddin explains meaning of Muslim Hajj. Hosts/Producer: Mamoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: film critic Anissa Bouziane, Muslim teacher Sommieh Uddin. Topics: Algerian Rai Music, Islam, The Muslim Hajj.)
  - May 10, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:44); (Lecture by McCloud on Muslims and the West at Columbia University, NY; Farid Umbay reports on the Columbia University Conference; music and poetry composition by Gonzalez, review of UK feature film "Brothers in Trouble" by Barbara Nimri Aziz. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim. Interviewees/Guests: Ryme Katkhouda, DePaul University Professor Amina B. McCloud; sufi composer Ibrahim Gonzalez, Barbara Nimri Aziz. Topics: Islam and the West, Muslim Americans; African American Muslims; Farid Unbay Pres. of Columbia Univ. Muslim Students Assoc (MSA); sufi, Muslim-themed film.)
  - May 17, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:16); (Bouziane reviews Bosnian director, Haddad talks about Muslim youth in USA and forthcoming DC conference on Jerusalem. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: film critic Anissa Bouziane; Prof Yvonne Haddad, Amherst University Prof. Topics: Film reviews Bosnia director Amir Costritso, Islam and the West, Islam, Christians in Palestine.)
  - May 24, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:58); (Aziz review of new Afghan alliances, announces Middle East films, Obeid Ramadan talks about Islam in his coutnry, South Africa, listener callins. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: listeners, Obeid Ramadan, South African Muslim student. Topics: Afghanistan, film reviews of NY-based festivals, Islam in South Africa.)
  - June 21, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:06:20); (End of talk by Siblani on Islam and Health, professor Asha Samad comments on female circumcision interviewed by Freeha Rubbani; death of Betty Shabazz. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Detroit health professional K Siblani, interns Ryme Katkhouda, Mona Al-Dahry, anthropologist NY-prof. Asha Samad, Sheik Ali of Family Circle. Topics: Islam and Health, female circumcision, Betty Shabazz, Iraq.)
  - June 28, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:54); (Sheik Ali reports on plans for the Malcolm X Shabazz Institute in NY; Berry describes Detroit-area Arab and Muslim history and Salam describes East Orange NJ Muslim community, Ibish reviews dynamics of Islam party in Turkish politics. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Ibrahim, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Sheik Ali and Mohamed, Hatem NY-Muslim leaders, Detroit community leader Michael Berry, NJ-elected rep. Jimmy S Salam, political observer Hussein Ibish. Topics: Betty Shabazz, Malik Shabazz (Malcolm X) Institute; Muslim Americans; Arab Americans, Dearborn MI, Turkey.)
  - June 28, 1997, (Activists offer details about results of sanctions on civilian population and calls for action; Ibish comments on CIA policies in Iraq exposed)
    - Part 1 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:32:07); (Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-activists Sara Flounders, Sue Harris, Sohair Sukkari, Rania Masri, Ryme Katkhouda, Iraqi refugee Maria; Icelandic activist Elias Davidson. Topics: Iraq, sanctions, anti-war actions, US policies.)
    - Part 2 of 2, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:17:51); (Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-activists Sara Flounders, Sue Harris, Sohair Sukkari, Rania Masri, Ryme Katkhouda, Iraqi refugee Maria. Topics: Iraq, sanctions, antiwar actions, US policies.)
  - circa July 12, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:01:52); (Review of death of Betty Shabazz; plans for the new Malcolm X Malik Shabazz Institute in NY, announcements, film review of Algerian directed; films; poems by Pauline Kaldas and Brenda Moosey; al-Radi describes developments in Uzbekestan. Hosts/Producer: Mahmoud Inbrahim. Interviewees/Guests: NY-Imam Sheik Abdul Latif Ali, film and Rai music expert Anissa Bouziane; poets Pauline Kaldas and Brenda Moosey introduced by Mona Al-Dahry; archeologist Selma Al-Radi. Topics: Betty Shabazz, Malik Shabazz (Malcolm X) Institute; Arab American poetry; Uzbekestan history and economy.)
  - July 12, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:50:38); (Farid Esack, described as a Muslim liberation theologian, addresses issues of Islam in South Africa and the struggle for liberation, and his reading of Qur'an. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Mona Al-Dahry. Interviewees/Guests: S African Muslim scholar Farid Esack, author of "Qur'an, Liberation and Pluralism" and member of the gender equality commission. Topics: Islam, South Africa, liberation theology.)
  - July 19, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:51); (Ibish comments on Saudi suspect in Khobar-SA bombing and US attempts at a final Israel-Palestine deal; Aziz interviews musician Al-Mudfaii in Jordan; Charara describes literary scenes in Detroit and NY and his family and poetry. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Mona Al-Dahry. Interviewees/Guests: political observer Hussein Ibish, Iraq musician Ilham Al-Mudfaii, NY-based poet Hayan Charara. Topics: Saudi Arabia, Palestine occupation, Israel, US policy, Iraq, music, Arab American poetry.)
  - August 2, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:44); (Commentators criticize Oslo Accords and its rejection by Israel, countering discrimination of Muslims, examination of 1996 US anti-terrorism bill, callins. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: commentator Hussein Ibish, film critic Anissa Bouziane, author Nita Renfrew, attorney Taif M Warren, Ibrahim Hooper of CAIR. Topics: Palestine, Middle East, media biases, Israeli policy, Oslo Accord.)
  - August 16, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:01:44); (Review of our program interns, callins, Sufi production by Ibrahim Gonzalez. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: intern Ryme Katkhouda, Ramallah based critic Adel Samara, sufi musician Ibrahim Gonzalez. Topics: Palestine, post Oslo Accord, Sufi music and poetry.)
  - August 23, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:12); (Abu Saba reports on discussions with NJ governmentt officials regarding state economic ties with Middle East countries; Ibish reports on recent elections and new government led by Katami 18 years after revolution. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Murad Abu Saba, NJ-based observer; Amherst-based commentator Hussein Ibish. Topics: NJ-area Arab American community, Middle East Iran, election.)
  - August 30, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:02); (Yusef report on subjects and nature of the annual conference; announcements of Muslims in local politics, listener callins. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Kira Yusef, Chicago-based member of ISNA, intern Ryme Katkhouda. Topics: Muslim-Americans, Islamic Society of North America.)
  - 6 Arab American Poets series, November 3-5. 1997
    - Interviewees/Guests: DH Melhem, NY-based poet, author, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:37); (DH Melhem talks about her work and reads her poems. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Topics: Arab-American, literature, poetry.)
    - Interviewees/Guests: Haas Mroue, Beirut-Paris based author, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:56); (Haas Mroue talks about his work and reads his poems. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Topics: Arab American literature, poetry.)
    - Interviewees/Guests: Lamea Abbas Amara, CA-Based Iraqi poet, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:38); (Lamea Abbas Amara talks about her country and her work, also recites. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Topics: Arab American literature, poetry, Iraq.)
    - Interviewees/Guests: David Williams, author/poet, MA-based, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:29); (David Williams talks about his work and reads his poems. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Topics: Arab American literature, poetry.)
    - Interviewees/Guests: Mohja Kahf, AK-based poet, novelist, professor, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:29:19); (Mohja Kahf speaks about her work and reads her poems. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Topics: Arab American literature, poetry.)
    - Interviewees/Guests: Khaled Mattawa, Michigan-based poet, translator, professor, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:10); (Khaled Mattawa talks about his work and reads his poems. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Topics: Arab American literature, poetry.)
    - 6 Arab American Poets brochures (Folder 1)
  - November 8, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:21); (Bouziane's interview with director Chahine, NY exhibit of photographer Yasmine Bouziane; Hussein Ibish review Iraq response to US-UN inspections. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: intern Ryme Katkhouda, film critic Anissa Bouziane; political observer Hussein Ibish. Topics: Egyptian filmmaker Yusuf Chahine; Iraq, US policy on Iraq, sanctions.)
  - November 15, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:02); (Abu Sabe reviews Arab role in NJ elections, Ryme Katkhouda's radio profile of Palestinian village of Deir Yassin; Hussein Ibish comments on UN inspections leaving Iraq. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Murad Abu Sabe, NJ-based observer, Ryme Katkhouda, Amherst-based political commentator Hussein Ibish. Topics: state elections, Palestine, Deir Yassin village, UN sanctions on Iraq and its policy on UN inspections.)
  - November 22, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:54); (Sheik Al-Khalidin describes community outreach and education; Ibish comments on US and Russian policies regarding Iraq. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based Muslim Sheik al-Khaladin, Hussein Ibish. Topics: police brutality, civil rights, anti-Islam racism, Muslim Americans, Iraq and US policy.)
  - November 29, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:07); (Our US Thanksgiving Day program "Taking the Land" explores parallels between Palestinians and Native American experience. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Native American activist/producer Raven Silva, Palestinian editor/economist Adel Samara. Topics: Native American history, Palestine history, land loss.)
  - December 9, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:55); (Ibish reports on OIC conference in Tehran; Lisa Mohammed reads her new work, and Bouziane reviews North African films in NY-African Diaspora Film Festival. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: poet Lisa Mohammed, film-reviewer Anissa Bouziane, Hussein Ibish. Topics: Organization of Islam Conference, poetry, French-Algerian films.)
  - December 23, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:31); (Ibish comments on Jordanian political tensions and Jordan-Iraq strained relations; Awadallah reports on wider observance of Muslim holidays; part 2 of interview with Farid Esack edited by Mona Al-Dahry; Gonzalez's Ramadan music production. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: political observer Hussein Ibish, South African Muslim leader/author Farid Esack, NJ-Community rep Prof Hani Awadallah; sufi musician Ibrahim Gonzalez. Topics: Jordan, election, Middle East, Iraq-Jordanian relations, Ramadan, Islam, sufi poetry.)